Anas Alfaqeer



Contact

Address:

Syria- Damascus- Al-Hamra st.

Phone:

+963 955 803 197

Email:

anas.alfaqeer@outlook.com anas.alfaqeer1993@gmail.com

LinkedIn:

www.linkedin.com/in/anasalfageer-b21685ab

Personal Information

Date of Birth: March 3, 1993

Nationality: Syrian

Languages

Arabic- Mother Tongue

English-Fluent

French-Basic knowledge

Anas in a Glance

I started my career as R&D Assistant while I was studying at university.

After graduation, I worked with numerous private sector companies and had the chance to collaborate with various UN Agencies.

Supported by 8 years of professional experience, I currently own a small equity specialized in NMA-E Engineering Solutions.

Additionally, I have become an Electrical Consultant for several companies.

Objectives

To secure an appropriate career opportunity that utilizes my training and skills, while making a significant contribution to the success of the company.

Character

- Sense of belonging "I'm so grateful to have perfect rapports with all my employers"
- Social "my friendship network is very diversified and rich"
- Careful about the company assets

Skills

- Team Working
- Enterprise resource planning- ERP-
- Problem solving
- Time Management

Education& Certifications

- Master in Business Administration, Syrian Virtual University
- Bachelor of Electrical Engineering, Damascus University
- AutoCAD 2012 2D& 3D
- Micro Controllers, Specialist Sciences Center
- MATLAB 2014, Specialist Sciences Center
- PLC- In collaboration with Moeller, Specialist Sciences Center

Volunteering Experience

Massar Rose Discovery Center Project is an important Syrian Trust for Development

We volunteered to design the "Interactive Public Parks" on the Fairground in Damascus, responsible for research in the fields of landscape design, engineering and interactive outdoor activities.

Professional Experience

Research and Development Assistant

FAKT L.L.C AlMuhalab CO 2014 -2016

- Coordinate the tenders process within the R&D team
- Communicate with international clients and suppliers.
- Review contractual terms and conditions
- Prepare the pricing sheet, technical and financial offers
- Obtain feedback from clients
- Cooperate and support after sales service team

Projects Manager

NMA-E for Engineering Solutions 2016-2018

- Defining the technical requirements and feasibility of each project
- Outlining timescales, costs and resources needed to design and deliver an electrical operations project
- Negotiating with designers, engineers, contractors and suppliers
- Ensuring each stage of the project happens on time, on budget and to a high standard
- Developing step-by-step project plans
- Leading a multi-disciplinary project team
- Overseeing several aspects of a project at the same time

Planning and Estimation Consultant Engineer

NMA-E for Engineering Solutions **2018-Present**

Sham22 for interior Design 2019-Present

Almsouti For Interior- Zawaya for decoration 2021-Present

- Perform various functions which primarily involve providing detailed estimates for a project based on the Electro mechanic drawings, specifications, and scope of work.
- Responsible for providing complete quantity take-off, analysis, and estimate, and studies for all deliverables involved in the assigned scope
- Create, maintain, review and administer electrical construction schedules and plans
- Liaising with managers and engineers to discuss the progress of the project and address any issues that arise
- Ensuring that installation and operations conform to standards and customer requirements by preparing electrical systems specifications or technical drawings.
- Ensuring that all operators and stuff are conform to health and safety standard.
- Brings all elements of a project together, makes certain that all elements proceed satisfactorily on schedule and within the money allowed; and initiates corrective action as required.
- Evaluate and discuss the technical risks and set the initial plan to avoid it.
- Communicate with risk management to prepare action plans to decrease risk factors.

Professional Experience

Electrcial Engineer
Self Employed-authrized by the
Engineers Syndicate
2016-Present

- Design, implement, maintain, or improve electrical instruments, equipment, facilities, components, products, systems, and testing methods to examine product quality and capability—always adhering to organizational standards and expectations
- Direct or coordinate manufacturing, construction, installation, maintenance, support, and documentation to ensure compliance with specifications, codes, and customer requirements, maintaining project scopes, schedules, and budgets at all times
- Maintain system and component capabilities through rigorous testing, while tracking cutting-edge trends, searching for ways to improve functionality and efficiency, and implementing appropriate segments to keep production methods current
- Prepare comprehensive documentation for all electrical designs, including wiring diagrams for low and high voltage network/ Circuit breakers types/ Lighting devices/ Earthing System/ Security Systems, bill of materials, assembly drawings, and design changes, test reports, design-validation plan, and reports to ensure that installation and operations conform to standards and customer requirements
- Analyze project requirements and perform technical calculations supporting design, including electrical requirements, safety standards, and motor controls; develop and implement software databases to track production processes

References

Name& Company

Eng. Nouh Shakir

NMA-E for Engineering Solutions

Eng. Mazen Al-Jerf

Sham22 for interior

Alaa Msouti

Almsouti For Interior

Wael AlFaqeer FAKT L.L.C/ AlMuhalab Co.

Contact Information

Nouh.s@nma-e.com /+963 950 500 502

Mazensham22@gmail.com/ +963 933 461 840

Alaaeddinmsouti1986@gmail.com/ +963 962 262 576

Wael.fageer@fakt-me.com /+963 950 500 603